Complexity, this does not mean about only time.
It's also about the space.
So there is space complexity of an algorithm or a computer program that it is the amount of memory space
required to solve an instance of the computational problem as a function of characteristics of the end.
It is that memory required by an algorithm until it executes completely.
Exeter is space some time ancillary space is confused with space complexity, but the exhilarating space
is the extra space or the temporary space used by the algorithm during its execution.
So the space complexity in total is equal to the exhilarating space, plus the input space.
What does this mean?
Calculating this space complex.
For complete, for calculating the base complexity, we need to know the value of memory used by different
types of data types and variables.
Which generally varies for different operating system, but the method for calculating the space complexity
remains the same.
For example, if we look about the Boolean Boolean takes in the memory, one bite.
So one bite is equal to eight bits.
Also, the GAO, a car or any of these variables at the end Java, we see the Boolean and the character
C and Python.
These data structures are primitives.
OK.
Also, in databases like Serial B, the other things are being present.
If we took the short and unsigned short.
Or insisting in other languages, we have two bites and the float and and long it took four bites.
And sometimes they're long long, which is the long, double or double and Java Python and see the about
eight bites.
So what do we need to know here is calculating the space complexity by taking a few examples.
Let's see this method public and some it took imperative meter in A and B and return a plus B, so.
And a hair is a value.
And we said that the end has for.
Bites took about four bites in their memory.
So the variables A and B are integer types since they will take up to four bytes each.
We have also returned a statement, which is, in fact it is making a new variable for calculating A-plus
B, so consider a variable called sum or consider a variable called K.
Gay equal A-plus B, So we have created a variable K or a new variable for making the addition, and
we're returning this result.
This will make a new variable of type and and this means that we have four bytes for the return value.
OK, so the total memory requirement will be due for integer the above 30 meters plus four for the returning
value hence.
This algorithm always takes 12 bytes of memory to complete, which is constant, so it can be expressed
in Big O as of one.
So this algorithm in terms of space complexity, its complexity is of one because at this cost.
Now let's move to exercise number two in the complexity and find this space complexity of this function.